I will introduce you to the REF230 platform
that I have had the opportunity to develop
for 2 years, on a permanent contract at Soft Concept.
REF230 is a certification for a
commitment to quality service
provided by AFNOR. There are
3 types of profiles on the app:
the account managers, the
service providers (Vitalis and Présence)
and the brands (Lissac, Krys, et
cetera). AFNOR and the
brands will have the same menus.
Except that for the brands, it's going to be
filtered on opticians and retailers
will see the information in
read-only mode. So, here
the login page. If I log in like
AFNOR, therefore as a
customer service manager, I will have access to the
stores, planning, audits
and reporting, while for
service providers I'm going to end up with
Audits, Archive, Excel Export.
So for AFNOR, AFNOR can, as
administrator, define the list of
TC, so the account managers and
follow-up emails.
The stores. There are 2 types of
stores: certified stores and
new stores.
Certified stores are those that have
REF230 certification in the
past. So I would like to point out, here we have a
version REF. In fact, we have 2
applications, one that is for the
version 2 and another for
version 3. Here I present only the
version 2. So certified stores and
new stores. For a store,
we're going to have a company name, the name
TC, a certificate number, a end date
of validity of the certification,
the version as mentioned and the
different actions as before.
These are the same for certified stores
and new stores. New stores,
being the stores that did not receive
certification. So, we can
make comments on the
store. The
store sheet, you can also import
files, we can fill in the
AFNOR account manager, you can
delete the store and you can run the
optical process. So we also have
filters and you can filter by
the sign, so for example Krys, the
file number, the TC (responsible for
clientele) and other
information: advanced filters (postal
code, staff, status, et cetera,
commitment 16, commitment 17, legal situation).
And you can also select
one store at a time. We can also
launch several processes at the same time,
so we'll be able to select
and click here to launch
optical processes.  Now, we're going to do
for an example, a single store. First, it
will be a new store since it will
has not been certified a priori. Therefore
we go to New stores and we
will add it.
So "Test",
FINESS number, store type (
franchisee or independent).
You can fill in the number of staff in the store,
So for example, if we put an employee,
We will be able to inform an employee
Here, therefore by
example Roger Federer.
Function:
optician, entitled diplomas with
university, year, number of hours per
week, 35 hours.
We can't add more
since we have provided information to a person. One
returns.
The city, Paris for example,
store email, I'm going to put my
email, we'll see that we're going to receive a
email during the process.
After the list of establishments, the
store opening hours,
any potential unavailability,
commitments, services, etc.
So the store has been added, it is
here. So
we will be able to modify the
store sheet, import files. There,
we are going to add a customer service manager.
That's it, I validate. So I'm going to
to be able to start the optical process. There
it has passed
in Planning, To be processed. Therefore,
we're going to have dates that have been
self-informed
according to specific calculations. One
will be able to filter. There are
already the Test filter on the test. If
we remove, we can
have them all. We can export to
Excel, export to PDF.
You can also filter on the empty
brands. So we can mark as read or
unread, like on Outlook for example,
on the messaging systems. We will be able to leave
comments on the service. We will
be able to change the audit period that
is programmed because there we see that
there are theoretical dates, the dates
programmed that may eventually be
changed, modify the store record,
download the data sheet or
import files. To be able to do
a request for application, which will be
is that the optician will
fill in information to
complete the store sheet. We will be able to
skip the step if the sheet is already
filled correctly. For example, if I
apply for a certification.
In fact I'm going to send an email to
the optician among others at my address
since it is the one I have filled in
when creating the "Test" store.
So there, the email is auto
created, the validated template.
It was sent to Test so there he
has moved to Sent
here.
For my part, I received an email
for the application file to
fill in, the instructions for filling in
the dematerialized application file,
complete the data sheet. I have to
fill in any information that
I wouldn't have mentioned or filled in
the documents that are requested of me.
For example, we're going to have a letter
of commitment, a K-bis extract, a
Security Clearance certificate
the ADELI certificate, etc.
So we're going to assume that he already has
filled in correctly what was needed. One
can possibly follow up with the optician
if he has not answered. We can
also suspend at any time the
application or delete it. It
will be found in the tabs here:
Suspended and Deleted. We can also
skip the step. So that's what we're going to
do in fact. We're going to start from the principle
that the optician has filled in his data
sheet already before.
Otherwise, indeed, he has to go
to the end of the process in the email.
So it is now validated, we
find it here. So there, we can modify
the period, the date of the audit period
programmed, we can ask for
complements afterwards, we can warn
the optician that we are going to validate his
application or we can jump
step without notifying it, so the
put directly to Requests for audit but
without email. We can possibly
fill in the unavailabilities and after
it's the same actions as before.
So what we're going to do is we're going to
validate and notify the optician.
So now I'm going to receive a new email.
There, it's in Requests for audit.
No Reply:admissibility of the application
I received the email.
If the date still suits us, we will
therefore have to inform the service provider
either Vitalis or Presence.
We're going to put Vitalis. Therefore,
first of all, you have to validate
the request for an audit so that
the service provider can have access.
We're still in the planning phase, I
reminds. Once the application is
audit done, in fact it will pass through
Audit. For the sake of confidentiality,
I will not present the part
provider. But the idea is that the
service provider will be able to use its
internal tool and platform to
provide information about the audit,
fill in the
non-conformity sheets and then the whole process
will be tracked between Planned, Completed,
Non-compliant, Validation Rep. Client and
Decision-making. Knowing that Planned,
it's going to be once the
planning has been validated,
Realized that the date has passed.
Non-compliant, there are non-compliances
that have been provided by the
provider. Validation Rep. Client
is that the non-compliances have been
treated, it will be corrected or
directly compliant and
then it will be sent to Decision-making.
There will be two experts who
will be able to validate the decision and after that
will wrap. And it's going to come back in
Planification. A process will have to be launched
with auto-incrementing dates.
So, Archive. We're going to have the finished,
So those who have completed, the
reporting (number of certified audits,
number of planned audits, non-compliances
distribution, the distribution of realizations
by month, the distribution of
planifications per month. There will be
also a map with the different
stores, an XML file as well.
You can always filter by brand, TC
and audit type.
We can disconnect.